# **Angelica Figueroa**

Dedicated and compassionate with 5+ years of professional experience in the education system. Seeking the role of a School Counselor within the K-12 setting. Eager to provide students with a positive direction for their social/emotional, college career readiness and academic, student's overall well-being.

#### **Education**

California State University, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, Ca-Bachelors of Arts in Communicative Disorders

Fall 2014- Spring 2019

University of Southern California, Los Angeles, CA— Masters of Education in Educational Counseling w/ PPS- Pupil Personnel Service Credential

Fall 2019- Summer 2021

## **Experience**

# El Rancho Unified School District-School Counseling Intern

North Park Academy of the Arts Middle School

January 2021- Present

- Diverse academic counseling with students
- Maintain accurate students records
- Effective communication between students, parents, and faculty
- Conduct weekly check- ins with at risk students to help them overcome personal, social, behavior, and emotional problems
- Consuel students individually and in groups regarding educational and behavior issues Monitor students absences and assisted during SART meetings
- Motivate students and parents during difficult times
- Attend and actively participate in SST/IEP/504 meetings
- Collaborate with other counselors in the district to benefit students in need of support

El Rancho High School

August 2020- December 2020

- Developed and implemented short term intervention and prevention strategies
- Actively participated in SST/IEP/ 504 meetings
- Identified areas of concern, seeked out resources to support and improve self- efficacy
- Conducted individual and group counseling sessions
- Maintained positive relationships in responses to family emergencies
- Learned to deescalated situations
- Assisted seniors with FAFSA/ College applications/ Career planning/ Class registration

# University of Southern California, AmeriCorps — Corps Member

August 2019- March 2020

Implemented Jumpstart Curriculum in a pre-school classroom and serves as an aid to teachers

#### City of Carson — Recreational Assistant 2

June 2018- March 2020

- Led free play and teach activities for various age groups, taught fundamentals of play and sportsmanship in recreational activity.
- Demonstrated and assisted in new and original games.

### Los Angeles Unified School District- Teacher Assistant

September 2015- August 2019

122 Elementary School/Los Angeles, Ca

- Prepared classroom lesson, special talent for supervising students, skilled in implementing lessons and information in the absence of the teacher.
- Track record for creating and maintaining effective student- teacher relationships.
- Profound ability to work in a stressful environment and able to assume a mentor's role

7942 Telegraph RD. Downey, CA, 90240 (323) 945-8412

figueroaangelica96@gmail.com

#### **SKILLS**

Classroom Guidance **Culturally Competent** Conflict Resolution **Developmental Awareness** Communication Critical Thinking Counseling Skills Collaboration Crisis Intervention Strategies Social Emotional Training **Decision Making** Leadership **Problem Solving Restorative Practices** Tech Savvv Trauma Informed Practices Trained in Child Abuse Reporting Spanish-Bilingual

#### **Awards**

- Mental Health First Aid
- Mental Health Specialist
- Kappa Delta Pi AGG International Education Honor Society USC

## **Professional Affiliation**

American School Counselor Association (ASCA)